Chien-Hwe Carol Hong

Profile

Chien-Hwe, also known as Miss Carol, has been teaching dance since the age of 14. Also a performer and choreographer, former Miss Dance of Cape Cod, she has taught contemporary, creative movement, ballet and yoga to ages 3 and above for schools, studios and stage productions with master classes, workshops, intensives and faculty residencies on Cape Cod, Boston and Hong Kong.

Experience

Master Class Teacher, Boston University, Boston, MA Advanced Beginner Horton Technique, college level

Movement Lab, Green Street Studios, Cambridge, MA Apr 2012 - Present Structured Improvisation/Expression through Movement, All ages + levels

Oct 2012

Contemporary Dance Teacher, Dance Workshop of Hanover, Hanover, MA

Sept 2012 - Present
Intermediate and Advanced Contemporary Dance , Ages 12 + up

Creative Movement, Cambridge Performance Project, Cambridge, MA Sept 2012 - Present Introduction to Creative Movement + Story-telling through Dance for young children, Ages 4 - 6

Ballet Teacher, North-East Rhythmic Gymnastics, Woburn, MA

Sept 2012 - Present
Beginner Ballet for Gymnasts, Ages 6 to 14

Modern Dance Teacher, Mass Ballet, Framingham, MA

Feb 2012 - June 2012

Beginner, Intermediate and Advanced Modern Dance Technique, Ages 8 - 18

Yoga Teacher, The Breathing Room, Cambridge, MA

Oct 2012 - Present
Meditation, Breathwork, Core Strength and Vinyasa Flow, Open Level Adults

Education

Professional Workshop, Alonzo King/LINES Ballet, San Francisco, CA June 2004 Introduction to Creative Movement + Story-telling through Dance for young children, Ages 4 - 6

Bachelor in Fine Arts for Dance, Fordham/Ailey School, New York, NY

1999 - 2003

Major in Dance Technique + Performance

Honor

Emerging Artist Award, Green Street Studios, Cambridge, MA Winter 2012

Top 100 of So You Think You Dan Dance, Boston, MA Season 7, 2009

Miss Dance of Cape Cod, Cape Cod, MA 1995, 1996

Skills

My class focuses on creating a comfortable and safe yet challenging and exciting environment for dancers to build trust and coordination of the body, space and music through structured improvisational exercises that encourage full body exploration of dynamics and texture, to master a solid foundation of technique through basic movement language and to deepen the fluidity and freedom of movement through the practice and refinement of intricate, luscious and athletic phrase work and choreography.